

123 Main Street, Mobile, AL 12345 eLLis.c@youremail.com (123) 456-7890 Resourceful and energetic medical receptionist with eight years of experience in clinical and hospital settings. Proven ability to efficiently deal with all aspects of front office duties in a medical environment. Friendly and professional when assisting patients. Effective in handling office and administration tasks in a busy hospital or practice with over 100 physicians.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MEDICAL RECEPTIONIST

Mobile Central Hospital. Mobile, AL I December 2015 - Present

- Check-in and check-out patients and ensure that all paperwork is correctly filed
- ♦ Contact insurance companies on behalf of patients
- · Schedule and register patients to ensure minimum waiting time and increased patient satisfaction
- Answer over 60 telephone calls a day and deal with face-to-face inquiries in a friendly and efficient manner
- Maintain records for the cancer patient program for 200+ patients ensuring the accuracy of data and contacting
 patients for follow-up consultations and tests

MEDICAL RECEPTIONIST

Mobile Health, Mobile, AL I July 2012 - November 2015

- Implemented a new patient records system that increased information accuracy by 17% and cut labor time by 12%
- Registered new patients and captured all the required personal information
- Greeted and checked in patients for scheduled appointments
- Maintained appointment schedules for seven physicians in the practice
- Ordered office and medical supplies as required and negotiated rates with vendors to cut costs by 27%

EDUCATION

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Jefferson High School, Mobile, I September 2008-June 2012

KEY SKILLS

- Data entry
- Organized and punctual
- Friendly and professional
- MS Office

CERTIFICATIONS

 HI PAA Record-Keeping Certification, Mobile Alabama Health Association, 2018